physio-pedia.com 2018-06-24

# Physiopedia:Privacy and Cookie Policy - Physiopedia

## 1\. PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy applies to Physiopedia (charity number 1173185, company number 08530802) and ( **“we”, “us”, “our”** or **“Physiopedia”** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

This policy, together with our [Terms of Service](https://www.physio-pedia.com/Physiopedia:Terms_of_Service) (and any other documents referred to in them), sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully. By using www.physio-pedia.com (the “Site”) and/or sharing personal information with Physiopedia and its community of users, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. 

For definitions of terms used in this Privacy Policy and FAQs, see Section 1.19. 

### 1.1 What This Privacy Policy Covers

This privacy policy pertains to the use of the Site, and (i) the information and materials made available on the Site (the “ **Physiopedia Wiki** ”); and (ii) the related Physiopedia services, (collectively, the “ **Physiopedia Service** ”), and covers how Physiopedia treats personal information that it collects and receives from its users. 

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the Physiopedia Terms of Service. Your use of the Site, the Physiopedia Service and any information you provide on the Site is subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Physiopedia Terms of Service. 

### 1.2 What this Privacy Policy doesn’t cover

#### 1.2.1 Third party websites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Site, the Physiopedia Services and any other websites and services that are owned and operated by Physiopedia from time to time. Physiopedia does not exercise control over third party websites linked to or from within the Site. These third party sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer or other device, collect data or solicit information from you. You are encouraged to read their privacy policies before you enter into an exchange with them. 

#### 1.2.2 Advertisements

Physiopedia automatically receives your IP address when you visit the Site. Physiopedia uses this technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and related links that appear on the Site. Physiopedia may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of the advertisements and to personalise the advertising content (including pop-up adverts) to a certain audience. 

See section 2.1 of the [Cookie Policy](https://www.physio-pedia.com/Physiopedia:Privacy_and_Cookie_Policy#1._COOKIE_POLICY). 

### 1.3 The Information Physiopedia Collects and How It Is Used

#### 1.3.1 General

The information Physiopedia collects is set out in this section 1.3. Failure to provide such information may mean that you are unable to receive the Physiopedia Services or register as an Editor. 

You do not need to register for a Physiopedia account in order to visit and use the Site, however, you must register to be a Physiopedia Editor. For these no-registration-required services Physiopedia collects the following information: 

**General:** You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our Site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you fill in the contact form, apply for a Physiopedia account, register for an online course or event, or other social media functions on our Site, enter a competition, promotion or survey, and when you report a problem with our site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, personal description and professional information. 

**Cookies** : The Site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Site. This helps Physiopedia to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Site and also allows us to improve the Site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, see our Cookie Policy. 

**E-mail Messages** : Note that if you send an e-mail to Physiopedia we may retain those communications and your e-mail address in order to reply to your enquiries, fulfil your requests and to improve our services. 

**To the extent that you submit to us any personal data belonging to third parties, you warrant that you have the consent of that third party to submit such data to us, including for such uses described in this Privacy Policy.**

#### 1.3.2 Additional information collected from Editors

In order to contribute content to the Site you must register as a Physiopedia “Editor” (see the [Terms of Service](https://www.physio-pedia.com/Physiopedia:Terms_of_Service)). Physiopedia collects the non-personal information described above at Section 1.3.1 from Editors, and in addition, Physiopedia collects the following types of personal information from Editors for the following purposes (personal information is information that personally identifies you, such as your name, e-mail address or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information): 

**Information you provide** : When you register to become an Editor, Physiopedia asks you for certain personal information. Examples of such information include your full name, e-mail address, professional credentials and the profile information described below. We use the personal information that you provide to verify your professional credentials, respond to your questions, provide you the specific services you select, send you emails about Site maintenance and updates, and inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy. 

**Profile Information** : Editors must disclose in their public profiles their professional credentials, corporate and academic affiliations, and they must disclose if they receive, or expect to receive, any form of compensation for the content they contribute to Physiopedia, or any compensation related to medicine, medical information, or products and services related to the body. This is standard practice in the medical field and those policies carry over to the Physiopedia community, and are meant to encourage a “neutral point of view” with respect to Physiopedia contributions. 

**Your IP Address** : In addition to your profile, you may also be identified in the Physiopedia system by your IP address, the numerical address of the location from which you are connecting to the Site. That IP address may be traceable specifically to your computer, or it may only be traceable to the Internet Service Provider (ISP) you use to access the Internet, depending on what type of connection you have. In either case, Physiopedia will have the ability to link your IP address to your contributions on the Site, which helps to prevent abuse and fraud. 

**Contributions** : When Editors submit content to the Site, that information becomes publicly available throughout the world via the Site, and each such “post” will be attached to the Editor’s profile. Our policy is to store this material indefinitely and to ensure that it is always publicly viewable. Removing content from a Physiopedia article does not permanently delete that content. This does not affect any of your rights under applicable law. The features of the Site permit anyone to retrieve a previous version of an article and, if requested, may allow people to see content that was previously deleted. If the article itself is deleted, a copy will permanently remain on the Physiopedia servers and be accessible by Physiopedia personnel (again, this does not affect any of your rights under applicable law). 

**Other Data** : In order to maintain an open and transparent community, certain other data on Editors is made public through “user contributions” lists and by other users, typically in aggregated form. Such data might include the times at which an Editor edited content on the Site and the number of edits they made. 

**Email** : Other Editors may send email to you through the Physiopedia service, however your email address will not be revealed to them unless you respond, or possibly if their email to you is “bounced” back to them. Physiopedia may use Editors’ email address to communicate with them periodically. 

**Invitation emails** : You may choose to opt-out of Physiopedia invitation emails by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the invitation email. 

**Links** : Physiopedia may present links in a format that lets Physiopedia keep track of when these links are clicked. Physiopedia uses this information to improve the quality of Physiopedia services, to estimate traffic Physiopedia sends to third party sites, and to customise content and advertising. 

**Your contacts** : In order to invite others to connect with you directly in Physiopedia, you may enter their names and email addresses. This information will be used by Physiopedia to send your invitation including a message that you write. The names and email addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation and reminders. You may also choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts on Physiopedia. All information entered as private will only be viewable by you and will not be searchable by others in the Physiopedia network without your permission. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy as cover your own personal information. **If you enter the names and email addresses of any such third parties, you warrant that you have the consent of such third party to enter such personal data and thereby submit this to Physiopedia.**

### 1.4 Physioplus

Please refer to our Physioplus [terms and conditions](https://members.physio-pedia.com/home/physiopedia-plus-terms-and-conditions/) and [privacy and cookie policy](https://members.physio-pedia.com/physiopedia-plus-privacy-and-cookie-policy/) which set out how we use the personal information you provide to us for the purpose of receiving the Physioplus services. 

### 1.5 Public areas of Physiopedia

The Site is open to public viewing. Any information shared (including personal information) that you reveal is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service. You should think carefully before disclosing any personal information. What you have written may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes. As with any public forum on any site, this information may also appear in third-party search engines like Google, Yahoo, MSN etc. 

### 

**Sharing of information between Physiopedia companies**

If you subscribe to our Physiopedia Services, information (both personal and non-personal information) is shared between Physiopedia and Physioplus in order for Physiopedia and Physioplus to provide or improve services. 

**Sharing of information with professional associations**

Physiopedia may share personal information with professional associations, such as the World Confederation of Physical Therapy, for example, to recommend individuals for professional services, awards and to suggest that individuals are invited to present at conferences. Physiopedia requires that such parties agree to process such collected information in compliance with this Privacy Policy, and to take reasonable confidentiality and security measures with respect to such collected information. 

**Operations and Maintenance Contractors**

Physiopedia operations and maintenance contractors sometimes have limited access to your personal information in the course of providing products or services to Physiopedia. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content for the operation and maintenance of the Site. Unless you have acted to opt-out of receiving e-mails and newsletters from Physiopedia, these contractors also may have access to your e-mail address to send newsletters or special promotions to you on our behalf or to send e-mails to you for purposes such as conducting market research on our behalf. Access to your personal information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for Physiopedia. We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors 1) protect the privacy of your personal information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and 2) not use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services as required by law. 

**Advertising and Promotions**

Physiopedia may share non-personal information (such as anonymous website use data) with third-parties to assist them in understanding the Site, including usage of the Site and the services Physiopedia provides and the success of advertisements and promotions. 

**Legal Requirements**

If Physiopedia is under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligations, in order to enforce or apply our [terms of use](https://www.physio-pedia.com/Physiopedia:Terms_of_Service) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Physiopedia and its users or others. 

**Breach of Physiopedia Terms**

Physiopedia also reserves the right to disclose collected Information that Physiopedia believes is appropriate or necessary to enforce Physiopedia’s Terms of Service, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend itself against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of the Site, and to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Physiopedia, Physiopedia users or others. 

**Other**

In the event that Physiopedia is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, Physiopedia reserves the right to transfer or assign the information Physiopedia has collected from you as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. If Physiopedia is involved in a change of control Physiopedia will provide notice before personal information becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

In the unlikely event of Physiopedia’s bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganisation, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, Physiopedia may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used. 

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, Physiopedia will not share your personal information with third parties unless you have elected to “opt-in” to such sharing of your information. 

Please contact Physiopedia for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data. 

### 1.7 Your Choices

When you register as an Editor, Physiopedia asks you to provide us with certain personal information. If Physiopedia wants to use your personal information for purposes other than those described in this Policy, Physiopedia will provide you with an effective way to opt-in to such use. 

Physiopedia will not collect or use personal information for reasons other than those described in this Privacy Policy, unless Physiopedia obtains your prior consent. 

You can decline to submit personal information to Physiopedia, in which case you will not be able to participate as an Editor. 

### 1.8 Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, considering your application to subscribe to Physiopedia Plus and the processing of your payment details. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential, We ask you not to share a password with anyone. 

### 1.9 Information security

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although Physiopedia does its best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

### 1.10 How long we store your personal data

We will store your personal data: 

#### 1.10.1 in respect of Editors:

only for the period during which you are registered as an Editors, except that we may retain for example, your name for the purpose of crediting your work in respect of any articles and other works on the Site for such period as such works remain on the Site; and 

#### 1.10.2 in respect of personal data collected for any other purposes:

only for such period as it is required to provide the services to you. 

### 1.11 Updating personal information

You may update your collected information by visiting your profile page or contacting us. 

### 1.12 Access to information

Data protection legislation gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with such legislation. We reserve the right to charge a fee for such access in accordance with applicable law. 

### 1.13 Complaints, problems and correcting and removing personal information

If you have a complaint or problem or would like any personal data relating to you corrected or deleted, please e-mail us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#067467656e67636a46766e7f756f692b7663626f672865696b) We will forward your complaint, problem or request to the appropriate internal Physiopedia department for a response or resolution. Personal data will be corrected or deleted, as applicable as soon as possible following receipt of the request. We try to answer every e-mail within 2 business days, but may not always able to do so. 

If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy related problem, you may write to Physiopedia’s Privacy Office at: 

Physiopedia,   
10 Queen Street Place,  
London,  
EC4R 1BE,  
United Kingdom. 

We will notify you within 30 days of receipt of your letter to confirm your personal identifiers have been corrected or removed. 

You may also lodge a complaint with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office ([http://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)). 

### 1.14 Limitations on Removing or Changing Information

Upon your request, we will delete your personal information from our active databases and where feasible from our back-up media. You should be aware that it may not be technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to Physiopedia from our servers. 

### 1.14 Notification of data breaches

In the event of a data breach we will alert all affected Site users within 72 hours. 

### 1.15 Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. No part of Physiopedia’s Site is directed to persons under 16. If you are under 16 years of age, then please do not use or access the Site at any time or in any manner. Physiopedia does not knowingly collect personal information on the Site from persons under 18 years of age. 

### 1.16 International Users

The Site is hosted in the United Kingdom and is intended for and directed to users in the United Kingdom. If you are accessing the Site from the United States, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from the laws of England and Wales, please be advised that through your continued use of the Site, which is governed by English law, this Privacy Policy, and Physiopedia’s Terms of Service, you are transferring your personal information to England and you consent to that transfer. 

### 1.17 Changes to this Policy

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Physiopedia will post those changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, Physiopedia will provide a prominent notice. Please revisit this page frequently to stay aware of any material changes. 

Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions. Please exit the Site immediately if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy. 

### 1.18 Contact

For more information about Physiopedia privacy practices, or if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please e-mail [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#780a191b10191d14380810010b111755081d1c1119561b1715) or write to this address: 

Physiopedia,   
10 Queen Street Place,   
London,   
EC4R 1BE,  
United Kingdom. 

### 1.19 Physiopedia Privacy Policy Definitions and FAQ

#### 1.19.1 What is personal information?

Physiopedia defines “personal information” as information that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, home address, phone numbers or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information. 

#### 1.19.2 What is non-personal information?

Physiopedia defines “non-personal information” as data which does not identify individuals, whether on its own or in conjunction with other information collected by Physiopedia. This includes information that is collected from many people, anonymised and aggregated into groups so that individual users cannot be identified. 

#### 1.19.3 What is collected information?

Physiopedia defines “collected information” as both the personal and non-personal information that Physiopedia collect from users. 

#### 1.19.4 What is opt-in?

“Opt-in” as means you are actively indicating your preference to participate in a program, email, feature, tool, or enhancement on a web site. Typically, if you “Opt-in” you must provide certain information, usually Personal Information, to the website or otherwise actively indicate your choice or preference to participate in the website program. 

#### 1.19.5 What is opt-out?

“Opt-out” means that if you do not take some action you are indicating your preference to participate in a program, email, feature, tool or enhancement on a website. Typically, if you “opt-out” you must uncheck a box next to a stated preference or otherwise take some indicate action to indicate your preference not to participate in a program. 

#### 1.19.6 What is a Physiopedia Account?

In order for you to use some Physiopedia services, Physiopedia needs to be able to authenticate you and protect your preferences and personal information from unauthorised access. To do that, Physiopedia asks that you sign up for a unique account, typically secured by your unique email address, a password and your name. No account information is shared with anyone other than Physiopedia except as specified in the Privacy Policy or with your consent. 

## 2\. COOKIE POLICY

The Site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Site and also allows us to improve our Site. When you click on a link displayed on Physiopedia, Physiopedia records the fact that someone using your browser, as identified by your unique cookie, clicked on that link. 

### 2.1 What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file containing a unique string of letters and numbers that Physiopedia stores on your browser or the hardware of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is stored on your computer’s hard drive. On subsequent visits to the Site, the cookie allows the Site to recognise your browser. The unique string of letters and numbers in a cookie may store user preferences and other information. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. However, some features or services of the Site may not function properly without cookies. 

### 2.2 Information about our use of cookies

We use the following cookies: 

COOKIE PROVIDER  |  COOKIE NAME  |  PURPOSE  |  PURPOSE DURATION   
---|---|---|---  
Cookies used by Physiopedia and Physiopedia Plus   
Google Analytics  |  _ga  |  Used to distinguish users  |  2 years   
_utma  |  Used to distinguish users and sessions . The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  |  2 years from set/update   
_utmb  |  Used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  |  30 minutes from set/update   
_utmc  |  This cookie operates in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit.  |  End of browser session   
_utmz  |  Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached the site. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  |  6 months from set/update   
Sharethis  |  _unam  |  Allows quick and easy sharing on common social media sites (including Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and G+).  |  1 year   
Getsitecontrol  |  _gs  |  Used to identify the users browser, operating system, IP address and the page on the website they are viewing.  |  1 hour   
_gu  |  Used to distinguish users.  |  10 years   
_gw  |  Records widgets previously displayed to user.  |  1 year   
Cloudflare  |  _cfduid  |  Controls site access security  |  1 year   
  
### 2.3 Blocking cookies

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the Site. 

### 2.4 How do I delete a cookie?

Deleting cookies is different for each browser. These are instructions for popular browsers used. If you don't use any of these browsers refer to your browser's Web site for instructions. 

Internet Explorer: 

  * Select 'Internet Options...' from the 'Tools' menu. 
  * Click on “Delete Cookies...” from the 'Temporary Internet files' section. 
  * Click 'Ok' on the confirmation window that appears.

FireFox: 

  * Select 'Options' from the 'Tools' menu. 
  * Click on 'Privacy' from the top selections, then click on the 'Cookies' tab. 
  * Click 'Clear Cookies Now'

Safari: 

  * Select 'Preferences' from the 'Safari' menu. 
  * Click on 'Security' from the top selections. 
  * Click on the 'Show Cookies' button. 
  * Select the 'Physiopedia' cookies and click on the 'Remove' button. Or you can also 'Remove All'

### 2.5 Expiry of cookies

Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 30 days.
